<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: haproxy | Pierre-O's Blog]]></title>
  <link href="http://pierreozoux.github.io/blog/categories/haproxy/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://pierreozoux.github.io/"/>
  <updated>2015-03-12T21:02:40+00:00</updated>
  <id>http://pierreozoux.github.io/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Pierre Ozoux]]></name>
    <email><![CDATA[pierre@ozoux.net]]></email>
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[HAproxy on CoreOS]]></title>
    <link href="http://pierreozoux.github.io/blog/2014/10/27/haproxy-coreos/"/>
    <updated>2014-10-27T09:01:14+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://pierreozoux.github.io/blog/2014/10/27/haproxy-coreos</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>What are the best practices of running HAproxy on CoreOS?</p>

<!-- more -->


<h2>Dear fellow hackers,</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;m discovering CoreOS, and I have to say, I enjoy it, it&rsquo;s really thrilling to learn all this new and exciting technology!</p>

<p>I&rsquo;m trying to follow as much as possible best practices for Docker, 12-Factor App and so on. But for HAproxy, I&rsquo;m hitting the wall. So here is my problem:</p>

<p>12-Factor app recommendation for logging is to have a process that sends out logs directly to stdout/stderr, and then your process management has to catch it somehow, and you can do whatever.</p>

<p>In the other hand, Docker recommendation is to run just one process per container.</p>

<p>Until now, I was totally fine. Systemd was catching output from my docker container, and everybody was happy. But what about HAproxy?</p>

<p>So, I realised it was impossible to log to stdout except in debug mode. This is the solution I&rsquo;ll use for now, but I feel it&rsquo;s not that elegant&hellip;</p>

<p>The other solution I found would be to run a container with rsyslogd listening on docker_gateway:514, and then configure HAproxy to send it&rsquo;s UDP packets to this gateway&hellip; But well, it&rsquo;s not that elegant neither..</p>

<p>I&rsquo;m open for suggestions to make it wonderful!</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
